redwingshoe.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy

Effective Date: December 31, 2019   
Last Reviewed: December 31, 2019   
Last Modified: December 31, 2019   
Contact [dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com](mailto:dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com?subject=I%20would%20like%20an%20archived%20copy%20of%20privacy%20policy) for archived policies.

Red Wing Shoe Company, Inc. and its subsidiaries (“Red Wing” or “we”) respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your privacy through our compliance with this policy and applicable law.

When you buy shoes, apparel, or accessories from us, you provide some of your Personal Information to us. For example, we may collect your name, shoe or apparel sizes, your address, your email address, and your phone number. By using one of our websites, we may collect information regarding your apps, browsers, and devices, which help us to understand you better and provides us direction on what products may be of most interest to you.

We may collect information about your location when you interact with our websites or retail stores, which helps us offer features like locating your nearest Red Wing Shoes® store. We may also collect information about you from trusted business partners, including marketing and advertising partners who provide us with information about potential customers of our products and security partners who provide us with information to protect against abuse. We use various technologies to collect, store, and process information, including cookies, pixel tags, and databases.

We work hard to protect you and Red Wing Shoe Company, Inc. from unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, or destruction of the information we control and process. For example, we use encryption to keep your data private while in transit. We audit our information collection, storage, and processing practices, including physical security measures, to prevent unauthorized access to our systems. We restrict access to Personal Information to Red Wing Shoe Company, Inc. employees, contractors, agents, service providers, and select advertising and marketing partners. Anyone with this access is subject to strict contractual confidentiality obligations and may be disciplined or terminated if they fail to meet these obligations.

## WE COLLECT CERTAIN PERSONAL INFORMATION.

We collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer, household, or device (“Personal Information”).

We have collected the following categories of Personal Information from our consumers within the last twelve (12) months:

Category | Examples  
---|---  
Category A: Identifiers | A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, or other similar identifiers.  
Category B: Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)) | A name, signature, physical characteristics or description (such as shoe or shirt size), address, telephone number, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information.  
 _Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories._  
Category C: Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law | Age (40 years or older), sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), and veteran or military status.  
Category D: Commercial information | Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies.  
Category E: Biometric information | Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as, shoe or shirt size.  
Category F: Internet or other similar network activity | Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer's interaction with a website, application, or advertisement.  
Category G: Geolocation data | Physical location or movements.  
Category H: Sensory data | Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information.  
Category K: Inferences drawn from other personal information | Profile reflecting a person's preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes.  
  
Red Wing does not collect (i) Category I: Professional or employment-related information, such as current or past job history or performance evaluations, or (ii) Category J: Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99)), such as education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records. We also do not collect highly sensitive personal information, such as social security number, race, religion, sexual orientation, or health; however, in some cases we may collect your shoe or apparel size.

We obtain the categories of Personal Information listed above from the following categories of sources:

  * Directly from you. For example, from forms you complete or products and services you purchase.
  * Indirectly from you. For example, from observing your actions on our Website.
  * From our service providers. For example, from a third-party that validates the correctness and completeness of the Personal Information we collect.

## WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION TO BETTER SERVE YOU.

We use the Personal Information we collect for the following purposes:

  * To fulfill or meet the reason you provided the information. For example, if you share your name and contact information to request a price quote or ask a question about our products or services, we will use that personal information to respond to your inquiry. If you provide your personal information to purchase a product or service, we will use that information to process your payment and facilitate delivery. We may also save your information to facilitate new product orders, process returns, or inform you of any recall.
  * To provide, support, personalize, and develop our websites, products, and services.
  * To create, maintain, customize, and secure your account with us.
  * To process your requests, purchases, transactions, and payments and prevent transactional fraud.
  * To provide you with support and to respond to your inquiries, including to investigate and address your concerns and monitor and improve our responses.
  * To personalize your website experience and to deliver content and product and service offerings relevant to your interests, including targeted offers and ads through our websites, third-party sites, and via email or text message.
  * To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of our website, products and services, databases and other technology assets, and business.
  * For testing, research, analysis, and product development, including to develop and improve our website, products, and services.
  * To respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, or governmental regulations.
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it.

We will not collect additional categories of Personal Information or use the Personal Information we collected for materially different, unrelated, or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.

## WE SHARE CERTAIN PERSONAL INFORMATION TO BETTER SERVE YOU.

We may disclose your Personal Information to a third party for a business purpose or sell your Personal Information, subject to your right to opt-out of those sales (see Personal Information Sales Opt-Out and Opt-In Rights). When we disclose Personal Information for a business purpose, we enter a contract that describes the purpose and requires the recipient to both keep that Personal Information confidential and not use it for any purpose except performing the contract.

### Disclosures of Personal Information for a Business Purpose.

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have disclosed the following categories of Personal Information for a Business Purpose:

Category A: | Identifiers.  
---|---  
Category B: | California Customer Records personal information categories.  
Category C: | Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.  
Category D: | Commercial information.  
Category E: | Biometric information.  
Category F: | Internet or other similar network activity.  
Category G: | Geolocation data.  
Category H: | Sensory data.  
Category K: | Inferences drawn from other personal information.  
  
We disclose your Personal Information for a business purpose to the following categories of third parties:

  * Service providers.

In the preceding twelve months, we have not disclosed the following categories of Personal Information for a Business Purpose:

Category I: | Professional or employment-related information.  
---|---  
Category J: | Non-public education information.  
  
### Sales of Personal Information.

In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have sold the following categories of personal information:

Category A: | Identifiers.  
---|---  
Category B: | California Customer Records personal information categories.  
Category C: | Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.  
Category D: | Commercial information.  
Category E: | Biometric information.  
Category F: | Internet or other similar network activity.  
Category G: | Geolocation data.  
Category H: | Sensory data.  
Category K: | Inferences drawn from other personal information.  
  
In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have not sold the following categories of personal information:

Category I: | Professional or employment-related information.  
---|---  
Category J: | Non-public education information.  
  
We sell your personal information to the following categories of third parties:

  * Data aggregators.
  * Marketing and advertising partners.

## YOUR RIGHTS AND CHOICES

### You May Access Specific Information, Correct Your Information, Obtain Copies of Your Information, and Request We Delete Your Information.

You have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your Personal Information over the past twelve (12) months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request (see Exercising Your Rights and Choices), we will disclose to you:

  * The categories of Personal Information we collected about you.
  * The categories of sources for the Personal Information we collected about you.
  * Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling that Personal Information.
  * The categories of third parties with whom we share that Personal Information.
  * The specific pieces of Personal Information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).
  * If we sold or disclosed your Personal Information for a business purpose, two separate lists disclosing: 
    * sales, identifying the Personal Information categories that each category of recipient purchased; and 
    * disclosures for a business purpose, identifying the Personal Information categories that each category of recipient obtained.

You have the right to request that we correct or delete any of your Personal Information we collected and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request (see Exercising Your Rights and Choices), we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your Personal Information from our records, unless an exception applies.

We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service provider(s) to:

  1. Complete the transaction for which we collected the Personal Information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, fulfill the terms of a written warranty or product recall conducted in accordance with federal law, or otherwise perform our contract with you.
  2. Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
  3. Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
  4. Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
  5. Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 et. seq.).
  6. Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information's deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research’s achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.
  7. Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
  8. Comply with a legal obligation.
  9. Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.

## EXERCISING YOUR RIGHTS AND CHOICES

To exercise the access, correction, data portability, and deletion rights described above, please submit a verifiable consumer request to us by either:

  * Calling us at 1-800-261-0326.
  * Emailing us at [dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com](mailto:dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com?subject=I%20have%20a%20question%20about%20my%20privacy%20rights).
  * Visiting [www.redwingshoes.com](https://www.redwingshoes.com/) and clicking on the DO NOT SELL MY PERSONAL INFORMATION link at the bottom of the webpage.

Only you, or someone legally authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable consumer request related to your Personal Information. You may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child.

You may only make a verifiable consumer request for access or data portability twice within a 12-month period.

The verifiable consumer request must:

  1. Provide sufficient information to allow us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative, which may include: 
    * For non-sensitive information with a low risk of harm: Matching at least two data points you provide with information we hold.
    * For sensitive information with a high risk of harm: Matching at least three pieces of Personal Information you provide with Personal Information we hold.
    * A signed declaration under penalty of perjury from you stating that you are the consumer whose Personal Information is the subject of the request.
  2. Describe your request with sufficient detail to allow us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to your request.

We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal Information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the Personal Information relates to you.

Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us.

We will only use Personal Information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.

For instructions on exercising sale opt-out rights, see Personal Information Sales Opt-Out and Opt-In Rights.

### Our Response and Its Format.

We endeavor to respond to a verifiable consumer request within forty-five (45) days of its receipt. If we require more time up to forty-five (45) additional days (or ninety (90) days total), we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing.

We will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option.

Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding the verifiable consumer request’s receipt. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily useable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance.

We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable consumer request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.

### Your Personal Information Sales Opt-Out and Opt-In Rights.

If you are 16 years of age or older, you have the right to direct us to not sell your Personal Information at any time (the “Right to Opt-Out”). We do not sell the Personal Information of consumers we actually know are less than 16 years of age, unless we receive affirmative authorization (the “Right to Opt-In”) from either the consumer who is at least 13 but not yet 16 years of age, or the parent or guardian of a consumer less than 13 years of age.2 Consumers who opt-in to Personal Information sales may opt-out of future sales at any time.

To exercise the right to opt-out, you (or your authorized representative) may submit a request to us by visiting the following Internet Web page link:

Once you make an opt-out request, we will wait at least twelve (12) months before asking you to reauthorize personal information sales. However, you may change your mind and opt back in to personal information sales at any time by:

  * Calling us at 1-800-261-0326.
  * Emailing us at [dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com.](mailto:dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com?subject=Do%20Not%20Sell%20my%20Personal%20Information)

You do not need to create an account with us to exercise your opt-out rights. We will only use Personal Information provided in an opt-out request to review and comply with the request.

## NON-DISCRIMINATION RIGHTS.

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under this Policy or applicable law.

Unless permitted by law, we will not:

  * Deny you goods or services.
  * Charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties.
  * Provide you a different level or quality of goods or services.
  * Suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.

However, we may offer you certain financial incentives permitted by the law that can result in different prices, rates, or quality levels. Any legally permitted financial incentive we offer will reasonably relate to your Personal Information's value and contain written terms that describe the program’s material aspects. Participation in a financial incentive program requires your prior opt in consent, which you may revoke at any time.

## THIS PRIVACY POLICY MAY CHANGE.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will not reduce your rights without your explicit consent. We will indicate the date the last changes were published, and we will offer access to archived versions for your review. If changes are significant, we will provide you a prominent notice. **Your continued use of our Website following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes.**

## CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions or comments about this policy, the ways in which Red Wing Shoe Company, Inc. collects and uses your information described here, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under any applicable law, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

**Phone:** 1-800-261-0326.   
**Website:** <https://redwingshoes.com/customer-service>   
**Email:** [dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com](mailto:dataprivacy@redwingshoes.com?subject=I%20have%20a%20question%20about%20the%20privacy%20policy)  
**Postal Address:**  
Red Wing Shoe Company, Inc.   
Attn: DATA PRIVACY DEPARTMENT   
314 Main Street, Red Wing, MN 55066
